Alex Poshivailo

(602) 810-6489 | oleg.poshiv@gmail.com | Tempe, AZ 85283

https://github.com/olegaposh | https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexposhivailo | https://www.alexposhivailo.com

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer leveraging 10+ years of experience in banking, mortgages, and investments. Earned a Bachelor's degree in Computer Information Systems and Management and recently completed an intensive 6-month full-stack web development program at the University of Arizona. Recognized for a keen eye for aesthetics and attention to detail. An excellent interpersonal communicator and collaborator that works well on team-based projects as well as independently. Known for excellent complex problem-solving and adapting well to changes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | React | Node.JS | Express | MySQL | MongoDB | Bootstrap | Git | Jquery | Handlebars

PROJECTS

Washburn Real Estate | https://codydevloop-washburn-realestat.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/azu20/real-estate

- **Description:** Search and filter for properties currently on the market and save them to your favorites.
- **Role:** Implemented the authentication using AuthO. Setup the form page with validation. Created the home page and added design to the website. Used conditional rendering in React for a dynamic website experience.
- Technology: HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Javascript, Auth0, Heroku, Leaflet Map

My Cost Tracker | https://my-cost-tracker.herokuapp.com/login | https://github.com/olegaposh/my_cost_tracker

- Description: A cost tracker that keeps records of your daily costs.
- **Role:** Oversaw the project. Designed the login using Passport.js, utilized Bcrypt to hash the user passwords, deployed MySQL to Heroku, set up the server routes, and used Handlebars and Jquery to render the front-end.
- Technology: HTML, CSS, MySQL, Sequelize, Express, Node.JS, Bcrypt, Handlebars, Passport.js, Jquery

Google Book Search | https://book-search-react-2020.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/olegaposh/book_search

- **Description:** Allows the user to search for books and save them to their favorites.
- **Role:** Solo project focused on the MERN stack. Established the front-end, set up the API, created back-end routes and the database. Deployed it on Heroku.
- Technology: HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Javascript, Google Books API, Axios

EXPERIENCE

The Vanguard Group, Inc., Scottsdale, AZ Fund Access Associate (2017 - Present)

2014 - Present

Process booking of incoming shares, deliver shares to contra firms, share class conversions, and trade corrections. Utilized various financial systems such as WAVE, Beta, Vast, Surpass, and AWD.

• Reduced costs 15% by collaborating with a cross-functional team to implement process improvements.

Investment Specialist (2014 - 2017)

Serviced clients over the phone by processing transactions, resolving issues, and discussing investment options.

- Decreased client errors 32% by leading a project to simplify a new account application form.
- Obtained Series 7 & 63 broker licenses.

JP Morgan Chase Bank N.A., Phoenix, AZ *Mortgage Advisor*

2012 - 2013

Determined eligibility and answered questions for financing mortgages and home equity products. Coached new and existing employees and took on additional managerial tasks.

• Achieved 100% quality assurance scores and ranked #1 year-over-year by exceeding performance standards.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Arizona, Mesa, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Management: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Certificate of International Business: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ